MAI DO

617-356-2893 | 14 Parker St, Charlestown, MA 02129

do.mai@northeastern.edu

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/maido187
Github: https://github.com/maihoangdo

Objective

I am a US permanent resident who has more than 4 years of experience working professionally with strong business acumen in Finance and project management skill. Adaptable Data Analyst skilled in cleaning, interpreting and analyzing data.

Education

Northeastern University

Master's in Analytics, GPA: 3.89 Concentration: Statistical Modeling Boston, MA

Expected Graduation May 2021

Skills

Data Analysis tools: R, Python, Jupyter Notebook, Numpy, Pandas, SQL, Excel, Google Analytics

Data Visualization: Tableau, R Shiny, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Google Data Studio

Data Analytics: Data Mining, Database, Statistics, Business Intelligence, Data Modeling, Forecasting, Data Warehousing

Project experience

Health Insurance cost prediction

Apr 2020 - May 2020

- Collaborated in a team of 2 to predict the effect of age, BMI, children, smoking on medical expenses by using R to build multiple linear regression and performed data mining with regression trees and used decision trees for classification.

Global Infant Mortality Rate Analysis (UNICEF)

May 2020 - Jun 2020

- Managed a team of 4 to create dashboards on Tableau to analyze the distribution of infant mortality rate (IMR) and researched how maternal education affects the IMR in various regions in the world in multiple bar charts and maps.

Marketing Predictive Analytics

Jun 2020 - Sep 2020

- Collaborated in a team of 2 to predict the user's likelihood of buying a subscription as a binary output by using Python with pandas, numpy, sklearn, matplotlib and seaborn packages to perform logistic regression to fit the model.
- Applied KNN classifier to compare the difference in accuracy between models.

World Happiness Report

Oct 2020 - Nov 2020

- Visualized and performed multiple linear regression to determine the relationship between happiness score and GPD, social support, healthy life expectancy, freedom, generosity, and corruption.
- Implemented several machine learning algorithms to predict happiness score. Supported data storytelling and non-technical stakeholder to explore the result easily.

Experiences

Finance Associate

Vast Dental - Newton, MA

Mar 2018 - Feb 2020

- Built and analyzed the financial metrics monthly, including patient insurance, copays and claims.
- Ensured completion and patient satisfaction by analyzing patient financial and insurance ledgers, followed established financial protocols and treatment plans.

Finance Intern

Penrose Realty - Boston, MA

Sep 2019 – Nov 2019

- Collaborated with the Property Manager on budget and forecasting analysis, including maintenance of tenant receivable balances and reconciling bank statements.
- Compiled monthly financial reports and collaborated on team presentations for management and clients and assisted the management team with market research and deal-making.

Project Management

Novaland Group - Ho Chi Minh City, VN

May 2016 - Jun 2017

- Managed and inspected three main projects with almost 1000 customers from the preparation process to the completion of the projects.
- Decreased customers' debt and increased payment in advance for 62% of the projects.
- Prevented late payments and developed a project implementation plan.

Community Engagement

- Member of Women Who Code Boston
- Volunteer of American Red Cross Boston
- Photographer for Snapwire and Doordash.